Guide to the Harper & Row, Publishers Records,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Harper & Row, Publishers Records,
1935-1973
Harper & Row, Publishers.
153 linear ft. (ca. 183,000 in 358 boxes)
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library, New York, NY.
4078866
History
New York publishing company.
Scope and Content
Correspondence, manuscripts, contracts, memos., and photographs. The correspondence pertains to the publications of numerous important fiction and non-fiction authors. The files are particularly strong for authors included in two important historical series, "The New American Nation," Richard B. Morris and Henry S. Commager, editors; and "The Rise of Modern Europe," William L. Langer, editor. The files of Cass Canfield Sr. contain substantial material on Planned Parenthood and International Planned Parenthood.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into 1 series:
Series I: Cataloged Correspondence
Series II: Manuscripts, Documents and Art
Series III: Arranged Series
Series IV: Business Files
Series V: Financial
Series VI: Copyright Renewals, Contracts and Rights Reversions
Series VII: Booksellers
Series VIII: Cass Canfield Personal Files
Series IX: Planned Parenthhood and International Planned Parenthood Files
Series X: Photographs
Series XI: Photographs and Illustrations Negatives
Subjects
Planned Parenthood of America.; Morris, Richard B. (Richard Brandon), 1904-1989.; Commager, Henry Steele, 1902-1998.; Langer, William L. (William Leonard), 1896-1977.; Birth control.; Publishers and publishing--New York (State)--New York.; Literature publishing.; Editors.; Literature.; Scholarly publishing.; History publishing.; Authors, American.
Access Restrictions
This collection is located off-site. You will need to request this material from the Rare Book and Manuscript Library at least twenty-four (24) hours in advance to use the collection in the Rare Book and Manuscript Library reading room.
Access to all documents relating to personnel, financial, and executive committee meetings is restricted.
Acquisition
1972 M-72 Harper & Row, Publishers Gift
Related Material
Collections related by provenance: Harper & Bros and Harper & Row archives are available at The Pierport Morgan Library (pre-1900 files), the University of Texas Humanities Research Center (1924-1963), Princeton University Library, and Library of Congress (Magazine, 1869-1965).
- Series I: Cataloged Correspondence
  - Acheson, Dean, [n.p.]
  - Agar, Herbert
  - Akins, Zoe
  - Albee, Edward Franklin
  - Algren, Nelson
  - Alliluyeva, Svetlana
  - Alphand, Hervé
  - Ambler, Eric
  - Amis, Kingsley
  - Anderson, Margaret
  - Armstrong, Hamilton Fish
  - Astaire, Fred
  - Atwood, Margaret
  - Auchincloss, Louis
  - Aymé, Marcel
  - Babson, Roger
  - Bacon, Leonard
  - Balanchine, George
  - Baldwin, James
  - Ball, George W.
  - Balsan, Consuelo Vanderbilt
  - Barkley, Alben W.
  - Baruch, Bernard M.
  - Barzini, Luigi
  - Barzun, Jacques
  - Beard, Mary Ritter (Mrs. Charles A.)
  - Bellow, Saul
  - Bemelmans, Ludwig
  - Benchley, Nathaniel
  - Ben-Gurion, David
  - Bentley, Eric
  - Berle, Adolf A.
  - Berlin, Irving
  - Bernays, Edward L.
  - Bettleheim, Bruno
  - Bischoff, Albert
  - Bliven, Bruce
  - Bourke-White, Margaret
  - Bowen, Catherine Drinker
  - Bowen, John
  - Bowles, Chester
  - Boyle, Kay
  - Bradley, Omar N.
  - Breuer, Bessy
  - Brinton, Crane
  - Bromfield, Louis
  - Brooke, Sylvia, Lady
  - Brooks, Van Wyck
  - Buber, Martin
  - Buck, Pearl S.
  - Bullins, Ed.
  - Bunche, Ralph J.
  - Bundy, McGeorge
  - Burnett, Whit
  - Bynner, Witter
  - Calder-Marshall, Arthur
  - Caldwell, Erskine
  - Carmer, Carl
  - Carmichael, Hoagy
  - Carpenter, Don
  - Carr, Albert Z.
  - Carr, John Dickson
  - Carson, Rachel L.
  - Caspary, Vera
  - Cecil, (Lord) Edward
  - Chase, Stuart
  - Chayefsky, Paddy
  - Chiang Kai-shek, Madame
  - Childs, Marquis
  - Churchill, (Lord) Ivor Spencer
  - Churchill, Sir Winston Leonard Spencer
  - Chute, Marchette
  - Ciardi, John
  - Clark, Kenneth
  - Clark, Mark Wayne
  - Clayton, Will L.
  - Connelly, Marc
  - Connelly, Cyril
  - Cousins, Norman
  - Cousteau, Jacques-Yves
  - Cozzens, James Gould
  - Cronyn, Hume
  - Crosby, Bing
  - Dannay, Frederic
  - Darrow, Whitney, Jr.
  - Davidson, Lionel
  - Davis, Elmer
  - Day Lewis, C.
  - Deighton, Len
  - DeVoto, Bernard
  - Dewey, Thomas E.
  - Dillon, Douglas
  - Donleavy, James Patrick
  - Dos Passos, John
  - Douglas, Paul H.
  - Douglas, William O.
  - Doyle, Adrian Conan
  - Doyle, Denis P. S. Conan
  - Duke, Angier Biddle
  - Dulles, Allen W.
  - Dulles, John Foster
  - Duneka, F. A.
  - Eastman, Max
  - Eden, Anthony, Earl of Avon
  - Eisenhower, Dwight David
  - Engle, Paul
  - Ernst, Morris L.
  - Fadiman, Clifton
  - Farley, James A.
  - Farrell, James T.
  - Ferber, Edna
  - Finletter, Thomas K.
  - Fischer, Louis
  - Fisher, Dorothy Canfield
  - Flanner, Janet
  - Flower, Desmond
  - Ford, Charles Henri
  - Ford, Henry, II
  - Fortas, Abe
  - Fosdick, Harry Emerson
  - Fox, Dorothea
  - Freeman, Joseph
  - Fromm, Erich
  - Frankfurter, Felix
  - Fulbright, J. William
  - Fuller, R. Buckminster
  - Galbraith, John Kenneth
  - Gallico, Paul W.
  - Gannett, Lewis
  - Garrison, Lloyd K.
  - Gary, Romain
  - Gavin, James M.
  - George, Walter F.
  - Gleason, Jackie
  - Gold, Herbert
  - Goldberg, Arthur J.
  - Graham, Philip L.
  - Gray, David
  - Green, Paul
  - Gropius, Walter
  - Gunther, John
  - Hadas, Moses
  - Hale, William Harlan
  - Hand, Learned
  - Hansberry, Lorraine
  - Harper, J. Henry
  - Harriman, W. Averell
  - Hart, Moss
  - Hayes, Carlton J. H.
  - Hecht, Ben
  - Hellman, Lillian
  - Hergesheimer, Joseph
  - Herter, Christian Archibald
  - Hicks, Granville
  - Higgins, Marguerite
  - Highet, Gilbert
  - Highsmith, Patricia
  - Hillyer, Robert
  - Hoffer, Eric
  - Holmes, John
  - Holmes, John Haynes
  - Hoover, Herbert
  - Hughes, Dorothy B.
  - Hughes, Langston
  - Hughes, Richard Arthur Warren
  - Hughes, Ted
  - Humphrey, Hubert Horatio
  - Hurst, Fannie
  - Huxley, Aldous
  - Huxley, Sir Julian
  - Ickes, Harold L.
  - Isherwood, Christopher
  - Ismay, Hastings Lionel Ismay, 1 Baron
  - Jackson, Henry M.
  - Janeway, Elizabeth
  - Jenkins, Elizabeth
  - Johnson, Lady Bird
  - Jouvenal des Ursins, (Baron) Bertrand de
  - Kaltenborn, Hans V.
  - Kantor, MacKinlay
  - Kaufman, George S.
  - Kefauver, Estes
  - Kennan, George
  - Kennedy, Edward Moore
  - Kennedy, Jacqueline Lee Bouvier
    [ See: Onassis, Jacqueline Bouvier Kennedy]
  - Kennedy, John F.
    [In vault]
  - Kennedy, Joseph Patrick
  - Kennedy, Robert Francis
  - Keyes, Frances Parkinson
  - Keyserling, Hermann
  - King, Martin Luther, Jr.
  - Kinsey, Alfred Charles
  - Kissinger, Henry A.
  - Knopf, Alfred A.
  - Kollek, Theodore
  - Kraft, Joseph
  - Krock, Arthur
  - La Farge, Christopher
  - Lamont, Thomas S.
  - Le Gallienne, Eva
  - Lehman, Herbert H.
  - Levitas, S. M.
  - Lewis, Wilmarth Sheldon
  - Lilienthal, David E.
  - Lindbergh, Charles A.
  - Lindsay, John Vilet
  - Lippmann, Walter
  - Lodge, Henry Cabot
  - Lodge, John Davis
  - Longwell, Daniel
  - Loos, Anita
  - Lord, Russell
  - Loveman, Amy
  - Luce, Henry Robinson
  - Ludwig, Emil
  - Macdonald, Dwight
  - McElroy, Neil H.
  - McFee, William
  - McGinley, Phyllis
  - McKenney, Ruth
  - MacLeish, Archibald
  - McNamara, Robert Strange
  - Manchester, William
  - Mann, Thomas
  - Mannes, Marya
  - Marquand, John Phillips
  - Marshall, George Catlett
  - Marshall, Peter
  - Marshall, Thurgood
  - Marx, Groucho
  - Mason, James
  - Massey, Raymond
  - Matthews, Herbert Lionel
  - Maugham, Robin, 2 Viscount Maugham
  - Mead, Margaret
  - Meany, George
  - Mencken, Henry Louis
  - Menninger, Karl
  - Miller, Gilbert
  - Miller, Merle
  - Montagu, Ashley
  - Moore, Marianne
  - Moorehead, Alan
  - Morison, Samuel Eliot
  - Moses, Robert
  - Moynihan, Daniel
  - Mumford, Lewis
  - Murrow, Edward R.
  - Myrdal, Gunnar
  - Neuberger, Richard L.
  - Nevins, Allan
  - Niebuhr, Reinhold
  - Nimitz, Chester William
  - Nixon, Richard Milhous
  - Norris, Frank
  - Norstad, Lauris
  - Onassis, Jacqueline Bouvier Kennedy
  - Orwell, Sonia Brownell (Mrs. George)
  - Oxnam, G. Bromley
  - Pack, Robert M.
  - Palmer, Stuart
  - Parker, Dorothy
  - Parsons, Geoffrey
  - Partridge, Eric
  - Payne, Robert
  - Pearson, Drew
  - Penzler, Otto
  - Perkins, Frances
  - Perowne, Barry
  - Petrone, Christine L.
  - Plimpton, George A.
  - Porter, Cole
  - Priestley, John Boynton
  - Prokosch, Frederic
  - Pulitzer, Peggy
  - Radhakrishnan, Sarvepalli
  - Rascoe, Burton
  - Reid, Helen Rogers (Mrs. Ogden Mills)
  - Renault, Mary
  - Rice, Elmer
  - Rickover, Hyman George
  - Ridgway, Matthew Bunker
  - Rissel, Victor
  - Robinson, Edward G.
  - Rockefeller, John D., IV
  - Rockefeller, Nelson A.
  - Rohde, Ruth Bryan
  - Romney, George
  - Romulo, Carlos P.
  - Roosevelt, Eleanor (Mrs. Franlkin D.)
  - Roosevelt, Franklin Delano
  - Rostow, Walt Whitman
  - Rukeyser, Muriel
  - Rushmore, Arthur W.
  - Rusk, Dean
  - Sadleir, Michael
  - Salinger, Pierre
  - Sandburg, Carl
  - Sarnoff, David
  - Schlesinger, Arthur, Jr.
  - Schuster, M. Lincoln
  - Sforza, Carlo, Count
  - Shaw, George Bernard
  - Sheed, Wilfred John Joseph
  - Sheen, Fulton J.
  - Sherwood, Robert Emmet
  - Shirer, William L.
  - Shriver, Eunice Kennedy (Mrs. Sargent)
  - Shriver, Robert Sargent, Jr.
  - Silone, Darina Tranquilli (Mrs. Ignazio)
  - Silone, Ignazio
  - Sinclair, Upton
  - Skinner, Cornelia Otis
  - Smith, Merriman
  - Snow, C. P.
  - Sorensen, Theodore C.
  - Spellman, Francis Joseph, Cardinal
  - Spender, Stephen
  - Sprigge, Elizabeth Miriam Squire
  - Steegmuller, Francis
  - Steele, Wilbur Daniel
  - Steichen, Edward
  - Steinberg, Saul
  - Stern, Philip Van Doren
  - Stevenson, Adlai E.
  - Stickney, Dorothy Hayes
  - Stimson, Henry L.
  - Stone, Irving
  - Stout, Rex
  - Stravinsky, Igor
  - Streeter, Edward
  - Styron, William
  - Sulzberger, Cyrus Leo
  - Sulzberger, Cyrus Lindauer
  - Swope, Herbert Bayard
  - Symington, Stuart
  - Symons, Julian
  - Taft, Charles P.
  - Tagliabue, John
  - Tanner, Patrick
  - Taylor, Fred A.
  - Taylor, Telford
  - Terhune, Anice Morris Stockton
  - Thomas, Lowell
  - Thompson, Dorothy
  - Thompson, Llewellyn E.
  - Thomson, Virgil
  - Toklas, Alice B.
  - Trilling, Diana (Mrs. Lionel)
  - Trilling, Lionel
  - Truman, Harry S.
  - Tuchman, Barbara Wertheim
  - Untermeyer, Louis
  - Van Doren, Carl
  - Van Doren, Charles
  - Van Doren, Irita
  - Van Doren, Mark
  - Vidal, Gore
  - Vidor, King, 1894-
  - Viereck, Peter
  - Villard, Oswald Garrison
  - Wagenknecht, Edward
  - Wagner, Robert
  - Warburg, James Paul
  - Warren, Robert Penn
  - Waugh, Alec
  - Welles, Sumner
  - Wells, Thomas B.
  - Welty, Eudora
  - Wescott, Glenway
  - West, Jessamyn
  - West, Rebecca, Dame
  - Wheelock, John Hall
  - White, Katharine Sergeant Angell
  - White, Theodore H.
  - Whitney, John Hay
  - Wicker, Tom
  - Wilson, Edmund
  - Winterton, Paul
  - Wirtz, William Willard
  - Wodehouse, P. G.
  - Wright, Richard
  - Wynd, Oswald
  - Young, Whitney M.
- Series II: Manuscripts, Documents and Art
  - Atwood, Margaret
  - Barrymore, Ethel
  - Bowles, Chester
  - Bullins, Ed.F
  - Carson, Rachel L.
  - Childs, Marquis
  - Hoffer, Eric
  - Holmes, John
  - Jenkins, Elizabeth
  - Ludwig, Emil
  - Marshall, George C.
  - Mencken, Henry Louis
  - Onassis, Jacqueline Bouvier Kennedy
  - Roosevelt, Eleanor (Mrs. Franklin Delano)
  - Sandburg, Carl
  - Schweitzer, Albert
  - Shirer, William L.
  - Tagliabue, John
  - Van Doren, Mark
  - Wescott, Glenway
- Series III: Arranged Series
  - Subseries III.1: Trade Department Files
    These files were donated to the libraries in May 1972
    - A Misc. [n.p.], (1959-60; 1961-62; 1963-64) (Box 1)
    - Acheson, Dean, [n.p.], (1947-56; 1957- 58; 1959-61
      [First ed. sketches]
    - Adams, Rachel, [n.p.], 1958-63 (Box 2)
    - Adams, Sherman, [n.p.], 1958-59, 1960, 1961, plus book
    - Adenauer, Konrad, [n.p.], 1952-55, 1957-58
    - Alden, John R.1952-55 NAN
    - Algren, Nelson, [n.p.], 1956-62
    - Alsop, Joseph, [n.p.], June 1963-Jan. 1964, 1964 (Box 3)
    - Ambler, Eric, [n.p.], 1956-59
    - Amory, Cleveland, [n.p.], 1949-52; 1953-56; 1957-59; 1960; 1961-62; 1963; 1961
      [re. libel]
    - Anshen, Dr. Ruth, [n.p.], 1952-54, 1955-56, 1957-58 WPS (Box 4)
    - Astaire, Fred, [n.p.], 1935-57, 1958-59, plus book
    - Astor, Brooke, [n.p.], 1959-64
      [plus book]
    - Ayme, Marcel, [n.p.], 1958-62
    - BA - BH Misc. [n.p.], 1959-60, 1961-62, 1963-64 (Box 5)
    - Balanchine, George, [n.p.], 1954-56
    - Baldwin, Hanson W. [n.p.], 1949-54, 1956-62, 1963-64
    - Balsan, Consuelo, [n.p.], 1951 -- 6/51, 7/52 -- 6/55 (Box 6)
      [plus Churchill letter]
    - Barzini, Luigi, Jr. [n.p.], 1957-60
    - Barzun, Jacques, [n.p.], 1954-57, 1958-59, 1960-61, 1962-63
    - Bemelmans, Ludwig, [n.p.], 1959-62 (Box 7)
    - Benson, Ezra Taft, [n.p.], 1959-60
    - BI - BRN Misc.
    - Billington, Ray A. [n.p.], 1955-58 NAN
    - Bishop, James, [n.p.], 1958-59, 1960, 1961-64 (Box 8)
    - Bowles, Chester, [n.p.], 1952-55
      [(Yale Univ. Lib., 1982)]
    - Bullock, Alan, [n.p.], 1957-63
    - CA-CN Misc. [n.p.], 1959-60, 1961-62, 1963--6/64
    - CA-CN MIsc. (Box 9)
    - Carmer, Carl, [n.p.], 1959-60, 1961-64
    - Carson, Rachel, [n.p.], 1958-64
    - Cerf, Bennett, [n.p.], 1954-57, 1958 (Box 10)
      [And folder (no dates) permissions for READING;]
    - Clark, Senator Joseph S. [n.p.], 1963, 1964
    - CO-CZ Misc. [n.p.], 1959-60, 1961-62
    - Commanger, Henry S. [n.p.], 1946-54, 1950, 1955-58, 1959-63
      [ROOSEVELT READER]
    - Commanger, Henry S. (Box 11)
    - D Misc. [n.p.], 1959-60, 1961-62, 1963-64
    - Dangerfield, George, [n.p.], 1964 NAN (Box 12)
      [Missing 6/2002]
    - Deakin, F. W. [n.p.], 1960-62, 1963-64
    - Degler, Carl, [n.p.], 1957-60
    - de Rougement, Denis, [n.p.], 1955-61
    - Douglas, William O. [n.p.], 1949, 1950, 1951-54
    - Doyle, Conan, [n.p.], 1934-48 (Box 13 & 14)
    - Dubos, Rene, [n.p.], 1958-62
    - Dunean, David Douglas
      [Returned to Harper's 14 May 1973]
    - E Misc. [n.p.], 1959-60, 1961-62, 1963-64
    - Eichelberger, Clark, [n.p.], 1959-64 (Box 15)
    - Ernst, Morris, [n.p.], 1943-47, 1948-50, 1951-61, 1955-58
    - F Misc, [n.p.], 1959-60, 1961-62, 1963-64
    - Faulkner, Harold U. [n.p.], 1955-64 NAN (Box 16)
    - Filler, Louis, [n.p.], 1960-62 NAN
    - Fishwick, Marshall, [n.p.], 1959-61
    - Flanner, Janet, [n.p.], 1954-56, 1957-58, 1959-64
    - Flexner, James Thomas, [n.p.], 1957-60
    - Foot, Sir Hugh, [n.p.], 1963-64
    - Friedrich, Carl J. [n.p.], 1951-54 RME
    - Fromm, Erich, [n.p.], 1953-57, 1959-61
      [World Perspectives, see also Anshen]
    - G Misc. [n.p.], 1959-60, 1961-62 (Box 17)
    - Gannett, Lewis, [n.p.], 1958-64
    - Garraty, John A. [n.p.], 1959 -- 1/63 NAN
    - Gary, Romain, [n.p.], 1960, 1961, 1962-63
    - Gesekk, Arnold, [n.p.], 1946-50 (Box 18)
      [ Yale Univ. Lib., 1982]
    - Gilmore, Myron P. [n.p.], 1952-55 RME
    - Gipson, Lawrence Henry, [n.p.], 1954-57 NAN
    - GO - GZ Misc. [n.p.], 1959-60, 1961-62, 1963 -- 6/65
    - Gropius, Walter, [n.p.], 1957-61, 1962 WPS
    - Guess, William Frank, [n.p.], 1956-60, 1961-63 (Box 19)
    - HA--HD Misc. [n.p.], 1959-60, 1961-62, 1963-64
    - Hadas, Moses, [n.p.], 1959 WPS
    - Hagedorn, Hermann, [n.p.], 1958-62
    - Hagerty, James, [n.p.], 1955-60
    - Haggard, Howard Wilcox, [n.p.], 1939-50 (Yale University Library, 1982)
    - Hale, William Harlan, [n.p.], 1946-50 (Yale University Library, 1982)
    - Hausner, Gideon, [n.p.], Dec. 1961 - 1964 (Box 19)
    - Havighurst, Walter, [n.p.], 1960-61, 1962-63 Region of America
    - Haydn, Hiram, [n.p.], 1957-62 (Box 20)
    - HE - HN Misc. [n.p.], 1959; 1960; 1961-62; 1963
    - Hecht, Ben, [n.p.], 1956-59
    - Hicks, John D. [n.p.], 1959-61 NAN
    - Hindus, Maurice, [n.p.], 1937
    - HO-HZ Misc. [n.p.], 1959-60, 1961-62, 1963-64
    - HO-HZ Misc. (Box 21)
    - Holmes, John, [n.p.], 1959-64, plus book
    - Hull, Helen, [n.p.], 1955-63
    - Huxley, Julian, [n.p.], 1953-57, 1958-60, 1960-63
    - Huxley, Matthew, [n.p.], 1962-1964 (Box 22)
    - I Misc, [n.p.], 1959-60, 1961-62, 1963-64
    - I-J Miscellaneous. Special trade S & E, [n.p.], 1958-1964
    - J Misc, [n.p.], 1959-60, 1961-1962, 1963-1964
    - John Dewey Society, [n.p.], 1958-62 (Box 23)
    - Jones, Howard Mumford, [n.p.], 1957 WPS
    - Jovanovich, William, [n.p.], 1959-64
    - K Misc, [n.p.], 1959-60, 1961-62, 1963-64
    - K Misc Special Trade S & E, [n.p.], 1958-63 (Box 24)
    - Kimbrough, Emily, [n.p.], 1950-53, 1954, 1955-56, 1959-63
    - Kubie, Lawrence, [n.p.], 1960 WPS
    - LA-LH Misc. [n.p.], 1950-60, 1961-62, 1963 (Box 25)
    - Langer, William L. [n.p.], 1948-54, 1955-57, 1958-59, 1960-63
    - Langer, William L. (Box 26)
    - Langer-Gleason, [n.p.], 1949-53
    - Larson, Arthur, [n.p.], 1958-63
    - Leech, Margaret (Mrs. Ralph Pulitzer), [n.p.], 1937-42, 1941-54, 1955-59
    - Leuchtenburg, William E. [n.p.], 1962-63 NAN
    - LI-LZ Misc, [n.p.], 1959-60, 1961-62, 1963
    - LI MIsc Special and Trade S & E, [n.p.], 1960-63
    - Link, Arthur S. [n.p.], 1953-56 NAN (Box 27)
    - Lippmann, Walter, [n.p.], 1946-54 (Yale University Libraries 1982)
    - Lord, Walter, [n.p.], 1957-60, 1958-59
    - Lundberg, Edgar F. [n.p.], 1946-49, (Yale University Libraries, 1982)
    - MA-MD Misc. [n.p.], 1959-60, 1961-62, 1963-64 (Box 27A)
    - Mc Kitrick, Eric L. [n.p.], 1960-62 (Box 28)
    - Marshall, Gen. George, [n.p.], 1959-60
    - Martini, Helen, [n.p.], 1953-62
    - Masters, John, [n.p.], 1958-59
    - Maugham, Robin, [n.p.], 1958-63
    - Mayer, Martin, [n.p.], 1959-60
    - ME-MN Misc. [n.p.], 1961-62, 1963-64
    - Mielziner, Jo, [n.p.], 1957-60
    - Miller, John, [n.p.], 1958-60, 1962 NAN (Box 29)
    - Mitford, Nancy, [n.p.], 1958-61, 1959-64
    - Moorehead, Alan, [n.p.], 1954-63 (Box 30)
    - Morris, Richard B. corr. re. Encyclopedia of American History, [n.p.], 1950- 63 (Box 31)
    - Mowry, George E. [n.p.], 1946-64 NAN
    - Mumford, Lewis July, [n.p.], 1956-Nov. 1961
    - Murphy, Gardner, [n.p.], 1959-61, 1962 WPS
    - Murray, Pauli, [n.p.], 1953-64, plus book
    - Myrdal, Gunnar, [n.p.], 1956, 1959-64
    - N Misc, [n.p.], 1959-60, 1961-62, 1963 (Box 32)
    - Nabokov, Nicholas, [n.p.], 1958-62
    - The New American Nation Series, [n.p.], 1946-62
    - Notestein, Wallace, [n.p.], 1953-58 NAN (Box 33)
    - Nussbaum, Frederick L. [n.p.], 1951-62 NAN
    - Nye, Russel B. [n.p.], 1958-63 NAN
    - O Misc, [n.p.], 1959-63
    - Oakes, John B. [n.p.], 1959-63
    - P Misc (Pa--PH), [n.p.], 1959-64 (Box 34)
    - Parks, Gordon, [n.p.], 1962-June 1963, July 1963-1964
    - Philbrick, Francis S. [n.p.], 1959-64 NAN
    - PI-PZ Misc, [n.p.], 1960-63
    - Plimpton, George, [n.p.], 1957-63 (Box 35)
    - Plutzik, Hyman, [n.p.], 1948-64
    - Pomfret, John, [n.p.], 1964 NAN
    - Q Misc, [n.p.], 1959-60
    - RA-RN Misc, [n.p.], 1959-63
    - Raymond, Jack, [n.p.], 1962-63
    - Redgrave, Michael, [n.p.], 1959-62
    - Rickover, Admiral Hyman, [n.p.], 1958-62
    - Ridgway, Matthew B. [n.p.], 1955-59
    - RO-RZ Misc, [n.p.], 1959-63 (Box 36)
    - Rowse, A. L. [n.p.], 1955-64
    - SA-SD Misc, [n.p.], 1959-65
    - Salisbury, Harrison, [n.p.], 1954-58
    - Sandoz, Mari, [n.p.], 1960-61 Regions of America (Box 38)
    - Schoenbrun, David, [n.p.], 1957-60
    - SE-SM Misc, [n.p.], 1959-64
    - Shannon, Fred, [n.p.], 1956-57 NAN
    - Shapley, Harlow, [n.p.], 1956-57 WPS
    - Silone, Ignazio, [n.p.], 1941-58 (Box 39)
    - Smith, Lillian, [n.p.], 1958-62 WPS (see also Anshen folder)
    - Smith Merrian
    - SN-STH Misc, [n.p.], 1959-63 (Box 40)
    - Sprigge, Elizabeth, [n.p.], 1958-59
    - Steinberg, Saul, [n.p.], 1949-57
    - Stepinon, Aloisius, Archbishop of Zagreb, [n.p.], 1952
    - STI-SZ Misc, [n.p.], 1959-62
    - T Misc, [n.p.], 1959-64 (Box 41)
    - Tagliabue, John, [n.p.], 1959-60
    - Toynbee, Philip, [n.p.], 1961-62
    - Tynan, Kenneth, [n.p.], 1958-62
    - U Misc, [n.p.], 1959-63
    - V Misc, [n.p.], 1959-61, 1963 (Box 42)
    - Van Drusen, Glyndon G. [n.p.], 1958-64 NAN
    - WA-WG Misc, [n.p.], 1959-64
    - Wade, Mason, [n.p.], 1947-64
    - WH-WZ Misc, [n.p.], 1959-65 (Box 43)
    - White, William S. [n.p.], 1957-64
    - Wilson, Sloan, [n.p.], 1959-63
    - Windsor, Duchess of, [n.p.], 1952-54
    - Wohlstetter, Albert, [n.p.], 1963
    - Wolf, John B. [n.p.], 1950-58 NAN
    - Woodham-Smith, Cecil, [n.p.], 1954-57, 1961-62
    - Woodham-Smith, Cecil, [n.p.], 1954-57, 1961-62 (Box 44)
    - X-Y Misc, [n.p.], 1959-62
    - Young, Desmond Nov. [n.p.], 1949-1961
    - Z Misc, [n.p.], 1959-64
  - Subseries III.2: Manuscripts and Proofs Available
    - Stuart Chase The Most Probable World, ( Galleys, page proof) (Box 45)
    - Dunlop & Chamberlain Frontiers of Collective Bargaigning, ( mss. galleys) (Box 46)
    - Seymour Fiddle Portraits From the Shooting Gallery, ( mss. galleys, page proof) (Box 47 & 48)
    - John A. Garraty The New Commonwealth, ( mss., galleys, page proof) (Box 49)
      [New American Nation Series]
    - Orin J. Hale The Great Illusion., ( mss., galleys) (Box 50)
      [ The Rise of Modern Europe eries]
    - Foy D. Kohler Understanding the Russians, ( Galleys, page proof) (Box 51)
    - Gordon Wright The Ordeal of Total War., ( Mss., galleys, page proof) (Box 52)
      [The Rise of Modern Europe Series]
    - Paul L. Murphy The Constitution in Crisis Times., ( Mss, galleys, page proof) (Box 53 & 54)
      [The New American Nation Series]
    - Kate Simon New York Places and Pleasures, ( mss., galleys, page proof) (Box 55 & 56)
      [Revised Edition]
    - Kate Simon Italy: The Places In Between, ( Mss., galleys, page proof) (Box 57)
    - Matvin R. O'Connell The Counter Reformation, 1559- 1610, ( Mss. galleys) (Box 57A & 57B)
  - Subseries III.3: Miscellaneous Materials
    - Printed materials (Box 58)
    - Columbia History of the World
    - Columbia History of the World. Manuscripts #1 (Box 59)
    - Columbia History of the World. Manuscripts #2 (Box 60)
    - Columbia History of the World. Contributors' Galleys A-Z (Box 61)
    - Columbia History of the World. Corrected Galleys (Box 62)
    - Columbia History of the World. Corrected Page Proof (Box 63)
    - Columbia History of the World. Index manuscripts (Box 64)
    - Columbia History of the World. Notes on Contributors, ( ms. and proof)
    - Columbia History of the World. Odd page proof with contributors' changes
    - Columbia History of the World. Chronological manuscript
    - Catalogs, [n.p.], 1931-1965 (Box 65 & 66)
      [ See also Box 350; FLAT: Reprography proofs]
    - Columbia History of the World, ( Galley Proofs) (Box 367)
  - Subseries III.4: Editorial Files
    Mostly correspondence with and relating to the authors listed below
    - A, [n.p.], 1965-1966 (Box 67)
    - A, [n.p.], 1967
    - Aa-Al
    - Am-Ar
    - As-Az
    - Abrahamsen, Dr. David
    - Addeo, Ed.
    - Alexander, Franz
    - Alexander, Franz (cont) (Box 68)
    - Allen, Mel
    - Allen, Steve
    - Allen, Terry and Don
    - Alliluyeva, Svetlana
    - Allmen, Rick
    - Amer. Assoc. for Advance. of Science
    - Amichai, Yehuda
    - Amster, Lewis (Box 69)
    - Andrer, Steven
    - Andrews, Wayne
    - Argus, M. K. (Mikhail Jeleznov)
    - Ariss, Jean
    - Armour, Richard
    - Armstrong, Hamilton Fish
    - Armstrong, Lucille & Simon
    - Ashford, Jeffrey
    - Associated Features
    - Ata-Ullah, Mohammad (Box 70)
    - Atiyah, Edwrad
    - Atkey, Philip (Barry Perowne)
    - Atkins, M. E.
    - Attaway, Robert
    - Atwood, Margaret
    - Audemaes, Pierre
    - Auerbach, Charlotte
    - Auerbach, Leon
    - Axling, William
    - "Baa-Bar" - "Bro-Bz" (Box 71)
    - "Bro-Bz" (Box 72)